So far, we've applied these aggregation functions across an entire table.
截至目前 我们对整个表格使用了这些聚合函数
You now know how to count all the records in a given table.
你现在了解 如何对指定表格的所有记录进行计数
But you might want to count records across multiple subsets of data.
但你可能想对多个数据子集的记录进行计数
For example, as a sales manager,
比如说 作为一名销售经理
you might want to sum all of the sales of each paper type for each account.
你可能需要计算每个账户每种纸类的总销量
GROUP BY allows you to create segments that will
通过 GROUP BY (分组) 你可以创建分组
be aggregated independently of one another.
在聚合时相互独立
In other words, GROUP BY allows you to take the sum of
也就是说 GROUP BY 可以使你只
data limited to each account rather than across the entire dataset.
抓取单个账户的数据之和 而不是整个数据集
Let's work our way toward this answer by starting with the sums of
让我们开始找寻之前提出问题的答案
the quantities of each type of paper.
先对每种纸类的数量进行求和
Now, we want to create a separate set of sums for each account id.
现在我们想依据账户 ID 创建各自总和的集合
So, let's add the account id column into our Select statement.
我们需要在 SELECT 语句中加入 account_id 列
As you can see, this returns an error.
你可以看到 它返回了一个错误
As we aggregate in this query,
我们在聚合时
we're effectively collapsing the number of rows returned.
其实是在有效地折叠 (collapse) 返回的行数
In our previous query,
在之前的查询中
we collapsed all the way down to a single row.
我们将返回结果折叠至一行
The reason we're getting an error here,
我们这里之所以得到的是一个错误
is that we've included the account id column but
是因为我们这里添加了 account_id 列
this column isn't being collapsed like the columns that are being aggregated.
但是该列并没有像之前聚合的列一样进行过折叠
The query isn't sure whether to sum the account
所以此次查询不确定是要对账户 ID 进行求和
id as well or whether to make it into a grouping.
还是对其进行分组
We have to be explicit about this.
我们需要对其进行说明
We want to tell the query to aggregate into segments
我们要告知查询 将其整合为多个分组
where each segment is one of the values in the account id column.
每个分组是该账户 ID 列中的一个值
We'll do this using the GROUP BY clause.
我们可以使用 GROUP BY 子句
You can see that this isn't ordered intuitively, so let's fix that.
你可以直观地发现这个顺序不对 我们来修正它
The GROUP BY clause always goes between
GROUP BY 子句永远处于
the WHERE clause if there is one and the ORDER BY clause.
WHERE 子句 (如有) 和 ORDER BY 子句之间
the query expects it to be in the GROUP BY clause.
则应该将其放入 GROUP BY 子句
A column that's not aggregated and not in
如果有一列内容没有进行聚合且不在 GROUP BY 语句中
the GROUP BY will return the error we saw before.
则会返回错误结果 如前所示
This is pretty important and it's the key to correctly using GROUP BY statements.
这一点很重要 也是正确使用 GROUP BY 语句的关键
Again, you should always see any columns in
再次强调 没有在 SELECT 语句中进行聚合的列
the select statement that are not being aggregated on in the GROUP BY statement.
应该出现在 GROUP BY 语句中